rom.on.ca 2015-06-13

# Privacy Policy | Royal Ontario Museum

The Royal Ontario Museum (ROM) is committed to respecting the personal privacy of our website visitors. The following statement summarizes the privacy practices of the ROM’s website, informing visitors of why and how the ROM collects personal information online and how the ROM uses this information.

Scope: This policy applies to the ROM’s website only. We are not responsible in any way for the privacy practices of other websites, which may be linked to the ROM’s website.

###  What is personal information?

Personal information is any information that can be used to identify a specific individual, and includes such information as a name, a home address, home telephone number and e-mail address.

The ROM may collect information in a non-identifying and aggregate form to enhance our website design and to share with external groups for any ROM related business purpose. This information cannot be personally identified with a specific individual.

##  Our Privacy Practices

###  Personal Information

The ROM does not automatically gather your personal information. You may anonymously access our website. Personal information is only obtained if you supply it voluntarily when using our website, i.e. contacting us via e-mail, entering a contest, making a purchase, subscribing to our e-newsletter or registering for programs. In general, it will be obvious when the ROM is collecting your personal information because you will have to fill out a form.

The ROM uses personal information in a limited number of ways, foremost to complete transactions, deliver the selected product or service and to respond to questions or comments. _The ROM will not sell or rent your personal information_. We may share your information in the following situations:

  * To those suppliers or companies hired to deliver the ROM’s products or services, for example a shipping company that delivers a package.

  * In some instances, for example online registration for programs, visitors may be asked to submit credit card information for payment. Credit card transactions are managed by payment processing companies with whom the ROM has partnered. The ROM will not authorize these companies to use the information except for the express purpose for which it was provided.

In certain circumstances, the ROM may use your contact information to inform you of other ROM products and services. In addition, you may be provided the opportunity to be informed of the products and services of affiliated organizations and other carefully selected cultural institutions. You will have an opportunity at the time we collect the information to indicate your preference for receiving additional information from the ROM and/or affiliated organizations, and where applicable, for inclusion in information exchanges with other cultural institutions. _If you do not wish to have your information used for these or other identified purposes, tell us and we will respect your wishes_. The ROM will seek to require that such affiliated organizations and/or cultural organizations maintain appropriate privacy policies.

All personal information you provide is protected under the Government of Ontario’s _Freedom of Information and Protection of Privacy Act_.

###  Security

The ROM employs reasonable administrative and technical measures to ensure the security of personal information.

###  Children

Children should use the ROM’s website with the approval of a parent or guardian. Where appropriate, the ROM will specifically instruct children not to submit personal information on our website.

###  Information collected by technology

The nature of the Internet requires specific information to be exchanged between a Web visitor/user and the ROM’s website. The information collected does not identify you personally and includes:

  * Your IP (Internet protocol) address, a number automatically assigned to your computer when you visit the website.
  * Your Internet Service Provider (ISP).
  * Your type of operating system (Windows, Macintosh etc).
  * Your Web browser (Netscape, Internet Explorer etc.).

This information is used by the ROM as an administrative tool for identifying system problems and monitoring network traffic. The ROM does not attempt to link this information with the identity of the individual visiting our website, except when necessary to protect our service, site, visitors, or others.

Parts of the ROM’s website use cookies. Cookies facilitate the exchange of information from your Web browser to our Web server. Cookies enable you to use our online registration service and can tell us how you navigate within our site, which facilitates the improvement of the site based on user-activity trends. The ROM does not use cookies to obtain any personal information about you, including contact information. Your Web browser can be set to detect or reject cookies. However, note that some parts of the ROM website will not function properly or may be slower if you refuse cookies.

The ROM may use third parties to collect conversion tracking data and/or data for remarketing purposes (for example, tailored ads). This is for advertising purposes only. All data is anonymous: you will not be personally identified through this data and the ROM does not see any data or contact information on an individual level. These third parties may include, but may not be limited to, Facebook and/or Twitter. These services recommend that if you wish to limit access to this data as much as possible, enable Do Not Track (DNT) in your browser,  and/or opt-out of  tailored ads in your account settings, and/or adjust your privacy controls in each account.

##  Additional Information

Questions or comments about the ROM’s privacy practices should be directed to:

Join-Michael Poon  
Freedom of Information & Protection of Privacy Coordinator  
100 Queen’s Park  
Toronto, ON  
M5S 2C6

Tel: 416.586.5868  
E-mail: [jmpoon@rom.on.ca](mailto:dianes@rom.on.ca)

The ROM is accountable for its privacy practices on this website. If you are not satisfied with our response to your privacy concerns, you may wish to contact the Information and Privacy Commissioner of Ontario (e-mail: [info@ipc.on.ca](mailto:info@ipc.on.ca) and telephone: 1.800.387.0073).
